David Verde Alvarez

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

David.verde.alvarez@gmail.com | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Twitter</u>

SUMMARY

Hi there my name is David Verde, I'm a software developer with 3 years of experience,I'm a self-learner and that's one of my best qualities, I'm Looking for a Remote Full-stack Dev Job where I can use all my Skills to create and improve new ideas.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Development Student

April, 2022 - Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building multiple full-stack projects both independently and via pair-programming.

<u>microverse-js-Pair-capstone</u> — Tv Series Finder using API TVMAZE & It makes Easier to find Tv Series By Season, Chapters and description.

Built with: (HTML5 & CSS3, JavaScript and SASS Preprocessors)

Pair-Space-Travelers-Hub — Space missions booker & Use SpaceX API to show Missions and Rockets features.

Built with: (React & Redux, JavaScript)

<u>Leaderboard</u> — JavaScript leaderboard project using API for store data & User can create his own Scoreboard and save it in the Unique API ID.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, JS)

MICROVERSE

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

- April, 2022 Present
- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

ORGANIZATION

City, Country

Mate Agency

Jan, 2018 – nov, 2021

- Produced line automation for uniform design and production.
- Attracted customers through social media and web pages.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

April, 2022 – Present

Remote Full-Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

I.U Elias Calixto pompas

Advanced Technician, System Administration

Feb, 2015 - Dec, 2017

- Created a Database For a hospital patients sheets tesis.
- Acknowledge for create a "relation between music-background sounds and good workspace project".